[SPEAKER_00]: me in trouble on the gazette yeah yeah i knew him when he'd come around when he was a boy he told me one day he wanted a store i don't know uh he's been off the hook he probably cut my foot no he's a good fella i just saw him a few weeks ago down there
[SPEAKER_01]: OK, I've got your record here.
[SPEAKER_00]: You have?
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm going to really get you now.
[SPEAKER_00]: What kind is it now?
[SPEAKER_00]: You're going to jail records, aren't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Sheriff over there's got it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Adoki Mills.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's so nice.
[SPEAKER_01]: I tell you, I'd like to have you tell me, if you would, your years as a boy growing up playing baseball, who scouted you, your first
[SPEAKER_01]: professional baseball contract and experience, things like that, just as they come back to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'm very interested in this background.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, let's see.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's kind of complicated because I signed with Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've been in Wesley before.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in the Green Bar Military, too, in 1916.
[SPEAKER_01]: 1916, over here in White Sulphur?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, in Lewisburg, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: And how I went, the Pittsburgh club got me.
[SPEAKER_00]: How I went out of the deal, I don't know anything about.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've never seen a professional uniformed man either, don't I?
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were you pitching for before you went to Pittsburgh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you a professional?
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't any professional.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't you play minor league ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, that was when I went.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've been in West Virginia, West.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played in Charleston in the valley there and around the coal mines.
[SPEAKER_00]: You played with the college team?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was in West Virginia Wesleyan.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a team there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yes, they had a good one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those college teams, they had what they called tramp athletes in schools.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess you heard of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I don't think so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they had maybe had some professionals.
[SPEAKER_00]: experience around high schools have too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know one pilot, I won't tell you the school, but I'll tell you his name, down in the valley that he played with this high school team under the name of Prince, back years ago, football team.
[SPEAKER_01]: His name was Art Shires.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, Art the Great?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that was him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he from around here?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he's from Texas, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was on the Columbus Club, not him.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that was Rochester.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd say I'm reading about 33 or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd be good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you finish at Wesleyan?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: How many years?
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't finish.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't finish at Greenberry.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there about six or seven months, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went there more after I'd quit school.
[SPEAKER_00]: Me and my wife used to go through there and stop.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it isn't in existence now.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you happen to go to West Virginia Wesleyan?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's some fellas around in Beckley that went to Wesleyan.
[SPEAKER_00]: There in some way, you don't know how you started.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't tell the straight of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that Johnny Blood Days up there?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was there in 1990.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came a little later I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the next year I went to Greasy Neal had been there a year before too, see?
[SPEAKER_00]: Big John Kelston, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: They beat West Virginia once, 20 to nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I saw the picture of Big John Callison.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was next to Pearl Buck's home.
[SPEAKER_00]: He lived right close there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's dead now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had some Indians there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't know what I went through about eight years ago, seeing they had all these pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: Greasy Neal was there then.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's right up from where we are, Parkland, where we are now.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of my nephews married a girl from Parklandburg.
[SPEAKER_00]: She'd been to West Virginia, and he'd been to West Virginia about three months ago, and I can't remember her name, but I remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a professional ball player, come from there, by the name of Hoblitz.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it was right outside.
[SPEAKER_01]: We actually lived in Williamstown, which is a little up the river in Hoblitz, so it was right outside there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never interviewed him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't doing this then, you know, and I know he was a manager and played in first base at Redding when I went in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think he was a first baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I've played since then, I think, in Boston.
[SPEAKER_01]: I played with Ruth, I think, in the 1916 punt-winning team for Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: You don't know how Pittsburgh got a hold of you, then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, there's something now that's complicated.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had, before they could send you out of the league now, I had the tools, but I didn't know how to use them, and you had to learn how to use them then.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I had pissed again Duke Kane and Carnegie and Kiss Commandos and some of them with Wesley and the Pittsburgh Club.
[SPEAKER_00]: They saw me then, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were men around.
[SPEAKER_00]: My sign was Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: First thing you know, I got notice to report to Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: You have to ask waivers.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were 16 clubs, eight in American, eight in the National.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you ask waivers, you're going to send a man out or release him.
[SPEAKER_00]: In my case, they was going to send me to Birmingham, I believe, to learn a little something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the Pittsburgh Club claimed me.
[SPEAKER_00]: But these other, they'd be selling more clubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: It depends on the standing, how, and still today, I guess, who gets the claim on you, and then the American League, in my case, why, they did, so Pittsburgh Club was
[SPEAKER_00]: When it got to me and I wasn't getting in any ballgames, they couldn't send me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: You withdraw your waivers in so many hours.
[SPEAKER_00]: If somebody claims you in so many hours, well, they get you and they keep withdrawing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I quit and come down here above Charleston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Quit Big League Ball Club.
[SPEAKER_01]: It says you pitched 13 innings at Pittsburgh in 1920.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then you quit Pittsburgh and came?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was in, no, but I didn't get in no ball game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I quit and come down here and Mr. Dreyfuss sent me my two checks and I told him I'd quit.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he told me to come back.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I got in the first ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_01]: I did good the first one.
[SPEAKER_01]: What month did you go up, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I went to record it in the springs in Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went to West Baden, then we'd go to Hot Springs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Austin would be in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then you left the team maybe in May or June?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, sometime.
[SPEAKER_00]: He called you back up?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I did good.
[SPEAKER_00]: We leave them in the person, but the next one I got into, it was pitiful.
[SPEAKER_00]: They butted on me or scared or something, and Johnson... Who were they, the Giants?
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnson.
[SPEAKER_00]: They scored four or five runs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like a third baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the first baseman run together and all excitement.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were they trying to embarrass you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Who?
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't do anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm glad.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did McGraw give you the needle?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never said no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Phams did.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the one that said, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know what my name was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the Pittsburgh manager?
[SPEAKER_01]: Gibson.
[SPEAKER_01]: George Gibson.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he still playing?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he wasn't there until he had... couldn't ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pye Traynor come up then and sent him back and then he come back again.
[SPEAKER_00]: Traynor.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who else did they have?
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you remember the team they were on?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember that well.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's personal.
[SPEAKER_00]: I faced them both.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right field was Billy Southworth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Center field, Max Carey.
[SPEAKER_00]: Left field, Carson Digby.
[SPEAKER_00]: First base was Charlie Grimm.
[SPEAKER_00]: Second base was George Cutshaw.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shortstop was Buster Capeman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Third base, George Whitted, the pitchers were Babe Adams, Wilbur Cooper, a fella by the name of Hamilton, a fella by the name of Carlson, and then I don't know, two or three more.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yellow Horse come there the next year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who's the catcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yellow Horse, he was a tough Indian catcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the catcher?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Walter Smith was a regular catcher, the best, but he was holding out.
[SPEAKER_00]: He caught some.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe he caught me the first relief cage I got in.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Cliff Lee and a fellow named Manhattan.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the older pitchers give you, as a young pitcher, a lot of help or tips?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, now they did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was very fortunate.
[SPEAKER_00]: I ruined some with Alexander, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you ruined with Rambo, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would be later when you were in college.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He helped me a whole lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: He kept talking about the ground ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Old Pete, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, old Pete, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it wasn't with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went with him on some of the road trips.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't see nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know about later on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Usually, you know, before the public, if you're before them, the stuff starts and then it turns into a storm or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: The ball players I was with, I was in it about 20 years altogether, and I never could say nothing about none of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fine fellas, they had a sense of humor, but on the ball field they were pretty serious.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I don't know... Well, just all of them, I was in...
[SPEAKER_00]: American League, the National League, the International Coast League, American Association, Texas, and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me now, you're not listed here for 21, 22, and 23.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was sent to Rochester in about a month or two to George Stallings.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then in 22, I of course came back to Pittsburgh and went in training with them and went to Rochester again and then was traded to follow the name of Rohwer, an outfielder, was traded to the Pacific Coast, Seattle.
[SPEAKER_00]: From there, then the Cubs, I went to the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Pirates traded you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or you were still Pirate property?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they outstriped me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where'd you go in auction?
[SPEAKER_00]: Two in Alabama, Roarhorn.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in 1922?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, in 23.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was at Rochester in 22.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was started at Rochester, Pittsburgh, all year, 1920 only when I quit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I went back.
[SPEAKER_00]: to them then and went in spring training for about a month and they sent me to Rochester again to George Stallings.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was George Stallings to play for you?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was the greatest man that ever was, but he wanted to go by the book.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the one that gave me the name of the sheriff.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd call you everything that they was, but he'd take bread out of his mouth.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't sue him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the fellows that played for him, one of them was in the major leagues, said he was the same way.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're saying he's very good, but hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was good.
[SPEAKER_00]: Another thing, he wants that ball low all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where the percentage is, that's your ground ball, you see, to hit low.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was getting old.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd say, you know, if you pitch high, you want it right under here all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, you could hear him from the bench, you could hear him for a mile.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, I can go up there and hit that myself and I can't see.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd say all stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, he could see and he could holler there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just wanted perfection, that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you pitched the ball low,
[SPEAKER_00]: And you got beat, he never said a word.
[SPEAKER_00]: But if he got you, they got a base hit and beat you on the aisle or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fitchburg had all the major league clubs wanted him to take men over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had two outfielders and one of them took Speaker's place and one College place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sooner was the outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sent him over there, Corsier.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pittsburgh had, you know, Kerry Bigby and that bunch.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were quite a, quite a, quite a... You mean these, the big league clubs wanted these players to be developed by... Well, they simply... Well, the pitching was, he was the best on pitching and he hated for you to give a base on balls all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they always, all ball players are told stories.
[SPEAKER_00]: that played for Stallings.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had the greatest in the world.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, Paul, I was pitching one day.
[SPEAKER_00]: His name was Sherwood McGee.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he'd been with Stallings, and everybody played for Stallings.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why, they'd have something to tell about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: In a ballgame, it stopped for something, and he'd come over and said, Sheriff, should you help Teal George Stallings?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, what do you mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, that's based on balls in three and two.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he told me the story.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stallings had sold a Rochester franchise and bought the Montreal franchise in the International.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got sick.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was pretty old.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so they sent him to Haddock, Georgia, his home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, when the doctors got his charts down there, it was something they didn't understand.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, I don't know, but if you see any Bason balls or 3-in-2 SVs, I can tell you all about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He died about a week after that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was during a regular scheduled game in Chicago that he told me that.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, this would come up in another one.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd tell so much about him that he had an expression saying, take that uniform off and burn it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're a disgrace to it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So one time he told a young fella to do that, and he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, this young fella took the third one to win a runoff or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they went down to, now after this ball game's over, he's your father, he can do anything in the world.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never said nothing about it until that ball game started the next day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was rough.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they said, well, Mr. Stallings said, I guess you're going to send me to a smaller leg now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, what for?
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, well, I worked that uniform out.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, you did what?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I burnt that uniform up, that's what you told me to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he says, boy, since you've got a job as long as I stay in baseball, you're the best being ever, ever did do what I told him to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was, you know, he was the one that, he was in pretty near last place on the 4th of July.
[SPEAKER_00]: in Boston one time, and he fired them up and brought them out one at a time and beat Connery head first.
[SPEAKER_01]: Connery was never the same, I guess, after that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never said nothing, but when that ball game started, that pitcher, you know, he got Fred Merkel over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dude, he had to get some experience, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Fred put on a hit-and-run play one day, and Fred missed the ball and got the man and threw it out the gutter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hey, bonehead is right!
[SPEAKER_01]: Is this in Rochester?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You remind him about that?
[SPEAKER_00]: That Fred Burkle was a great, intelligent ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: This thing just happened there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was 19 years old, I think, when that happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was just a kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never outlived it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never allowed a piece of paper to be between him and the hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody would throw a chewing gum right around the stand over the dugout.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd make somebody... Merkle?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, old Stallings.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was superstitious.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, in the dugout?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was an immaculate dresser.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he always looked neat and tall.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he sure did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he helped me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I won 38 games for him in two years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you break that down in 21 and 22?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, 21 and 17.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went over a month later, the second year, you see, I won 21.
[SPEAKER_00]: You won 21 and 21, and 17 and 22?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they sent me over there later.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he had a fellow, Hapgood.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, George Stallings couldn't sign a ball player up.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't give him a ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: But this fellow, Hapgood, wasn't working his business plan.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Pittsburgh over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wanted more money.
[SPEAKER_00]: I knew I belonged to the Pittsburgh club, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went in the office one day that morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: I knew Stallings was sitting there with the door cracked open.
[SPEAKER_00]: Talked his hat good, and we couldn't agree on salary.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, why are Mr. Dreyfuss here in Pittsburgh?
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he's coming back.
[SPEAKER_00]: I started, I started like, hey, hey, where are you going there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Said, give him what he wants.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's pretty easy then to deal with on contracts, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what I say.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd give you the ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, did he own the franchise?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, he owned it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He owned Rochester, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he owned Rochester, and then he bought Montreal and wanted to come in.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did Pittsburgh have a working arrangement with him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, well, a lot of them clubs, they had so many ball players of big league, they wasn't quite ready.
[SPEAKER_00]: About every ball club there was, had a man over at Starbucks over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he had another one there that, you know when they won that pennant in 1914?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, whatever cars there was, the boys would have to borrow a car.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, he'd want to call somebody something.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't know what your first name was.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he did, he'd never call you that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He called you a lot of things he couldn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, he'd say, somebody do something, you Buick, Bum, Ford, Flopper.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, one day he forgot the cow done something, but he couldn't remember what it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, he called him a bicycle riding son of a gun.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've become the nickname of the sheriff.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought you were a sheriff.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've had that plaque up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's for the faded.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they got Sheriff Blake on that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I've got a lifetime pass here.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's on that too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, now, when I went there, down through here, from here to the Gulf of Mexico, it was all moonshine, you know, during Prohibition.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was stuck in big papers, you know, about the moonshiners down through here and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he went to call me one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, so many moonshiners, nearly.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went to call me something and he couldn't think of it and he called me a moonshining sheriff and it went through all of my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what they did and I've had to explain that a hundred times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was you a sheriff or no, I wasn't a sheriff.
[SPEAKER_00]: All that stuff there.
[SPEAKER_00]: My lifetime passed.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was at St. Louis then when my
[SPEAKER_00]: Ten years was up, pardon me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come to the office, a fresh boy at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: He asked me how I liked it, and I said, fine, but I wish they hadn't put that sheriff on me.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, that's the way you know, they know you, and they're not going to change it for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got a lifetime pass for a 10-year service?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that true for all 10-year men?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it was then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it was a golden for 20, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if there was any then, 20 years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: It gets kind of dark like.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, look at that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Isn't that something?
[SPEAKER_00]: I never saw those.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever get much chance to use it?
[SPEAKER_01]: I've never used it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you haven't never did use it.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that's not what it's for anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you've got your identification, that's all you need.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't carry that around with you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anyway, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me, what was life like with Rochester?
[SPEAKER_01]: I mean, in 21-22, the play conditions, the ballpark, the travel,
[SPEAKER_01]: food, that kind of thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was living like?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was, it was fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, you didn't have to pass the ball around.
[SPEAKER_00]: You did pretty good.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had, Trona was in the play bed, and we'd ride the boat across the lake.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a night boat ride, eh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Night boat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Redding was in it then, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd have to call a hobbit, so we'd just tell you he was a man, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: First base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I liked that rig.
[SPEAKER_00]: It went good all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: This boat ride, did you get much sleep?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, you had cabins on all night.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was an all-night ride across the whole of Ontario.
[SPEAKER_01]: Had you been traveling by boat before?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was 90 miles, I believe, across from Rochester to Toronto.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wouldn't be a night boat all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lost when the Cubs got me from Seattle.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lost 19 games, only won 13.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a pitcher on the club, won 25, lost about 10.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wanted him to get me and turn him back.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a lot younger than he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was that?
[SPEAKER_00]: The pitcher, Elmer Jacobs.
[SPEAKER_00]: come back later on some of the other clubs that had been in the major leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: We played, I believe, in the Coast League, I believe, about two months.
[SPEAKER_00]: You were 13 and 19?
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that your record?
[SPEAKER_00]: Lost 19 and won 13.
[SPEAKER_00]: With Seattle.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the Cubs brought you there?
[SPEAKER_00]: They did.
[SPEAKER_01]: They kept me.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did they come across you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they scout you there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Dorr, me and him became great friends later on.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a Cubs scout?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he carried a blank check of the old man's regulars, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh, Bug Clancy was in Chattanooga one time when he bought a ballplayer.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched to get him that day for $50,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought me and Bug Clancy, he'd be worth the price, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: We thought he was, uh, was going to get big barley.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched that day, and
[SPEAKER_00]: I just thought a boy didn't look so good.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I got him out, but I didn't bother you at the boy's home.
[SPEAKER_00]: He excused himself, went upstairs, and he just brought Nicholson.
[SPEAKER_00]: Father Nicholson, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he helped him in the family.
[SPEAKER_00]: Barnard, he said, you'll get too heavy, and he said, you did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Scott's another business uncle.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, them fathers did then.
[SPEAKER_00]: They weren't bulldogs, really.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd look at a boy and they'd know what made them mistakes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who's your manager out in Seattle?
[SPEAKER_01]: Killebrew.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wade Willoughby.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an outfielder at Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: And his brother was a manager when I went to the club gym, Bill, the catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's one regret that I have in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: that I couldn't help win Old Man Wrigley World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: That old man never got the credit that was due to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He built up baseball, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was right after that thing happened in Cincinnati, you know, in 1919.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then Judge Landis come in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the most impressive man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever meet the judge?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: His dugout is
[SPEAKER_00]: His office was in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: As we'd come out of the dugout, he'd be sitting right there with a bunch of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were smiling.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wore a Piccadilly collar on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Piccadilly collar.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had kind of long hair and slouch hat.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was the most impressive man I ever saw.
[SPEAKER_00]: He liked to hung Branch Rickey if he could.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, oh, he, you know, he got some fun in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: a big shot up there, a Cadillac man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got him, found him, and turned some of his ball players loose.
[SPEAKER_00]: Probably cost him about half a million dollars.
[SPEAKER_00]: He broke some of his rules.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the judge know the players personally?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he speak to you at all there on that box?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, sir.
[SPEAKER_00]: He expected you to look at him, and that's about all.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't speak to nobody, and he never smiled.
[SPEAKER_00]: He weighed about 104,000, but he was dynamite.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet Ben Johnson?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see Heidler, I believe, was...
[SPEAKER_00]: He's nationally.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gary Herman.
[SPEAKER_00]: You met Gary Herman, did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, you never see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you see him now.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's from a distance, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that Landis, now, he's straight and clear.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he was the boss, he could run any owner.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think the owners are kind of sorry they hired him after a while.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, no, they didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: They needed that man in there, because baseball and the kids and everything was down on them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they had the second election.
[SPEAKER_00]: They tailed me for executing.
[SPEAKER_00]: 7-year term, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, of course, there's 16 clubs to vote, and the vote was 14 to 2 for him, Frank Rickey and Briggs.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did Rickey do now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he antagonize the judge so much?
[SPEAKER_00]: Ricky, what Ricky did, he had men to cover up for him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Judges had to attend.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, he had another hanging judge.
[SPEAKER_00]: He called Landis a hanging judge.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was from down south.
[SPEAKER_00]: He followed the name of Branham.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the National Association panel.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was...
[SPEAKER_00]: He took care of the minor ones.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you can appeal to Landis.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he never reversed the decision.
[SPEAKER_00]: a good brand mate.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got a picture of it in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now he'd do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have a minor league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody meets at certain places.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was at one in Columbus once and now I don't know, Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: All the clubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: After that's through with a big league.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's there, but you never see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's good.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stephanie told me about something.
[SPEAKER_00]: minor laborers down here at Portsmouth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Big shots.
[SPEAKER_00]: They did something and Judge Brown got them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they went to, thought they could go up there at this meeting in Cincinnati, you know, and see Judge Lantz.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he got by his office there somewhere and got in his room.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he went to his office.
[SPEAKER_00]: They asked him, Sarge Cox, what they was doing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they started talking, and he lit in on them, said he wanted to jump out that window.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, they wanted to see him about something happening in the mind of X.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was, he was impressive as he could be, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: The way he was a big man, you know, a scandal happened in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jody Landis was one of the biggest men in the country.
[SPEAKER_00]: He filed a standing order.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, nobody dared to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But federal judges had heard the case, but they wouldn't give no decision.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd give one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, whether they paid it or not, well, that wasn't done in his business.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he sure filed one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, baseball needed somebody like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got him, and he looked at the rules and he made some.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me, what did your father do in his business there?
[SPEAKER_00]: My father was a coal miner, and there was about six in the family.
[SPEAKER_00]: He worked for a dollar a day.
[SPEAKER_00]: We made it, we had plenty.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you work in the mines?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, I had 30 years in the mines.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just about 30, maybe more than that.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, since I quit now, I pulled 20 of that.
[SPEAKER_01]: You work in the mines?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I go in, yeah, I go in.
[SPEAKER_00]: I run a haulage motor.
[SPEAKER_00]: Main line, they call it, and I had one fella came sitting in the deck with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to get out and threw them back in.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got up and turned around and killed him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a boy then, wasn't I?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was on the engineering corps and electrician.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, my father became a general superintendent later on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where was the mine?
[SPEAKER_01]: Around here?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, right around Beckley and then Gawley Mountain up on Gawley River.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there were six in the family, Sam?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, there was.
[SPEAKER_00]: We worked for a dollar a day.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we had gardens and raised stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: And while we went home...
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a pretty nice home despite having to work so long in the mines, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was lucky.
[SPEAKER_00]: He fired me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't have any time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was on me all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd break one of his rules and he'd catch me and the other guys do the same thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I did.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, how'd you get a chance to play baseball?
[SPEAKER_00]: They worked in the mines.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, all these mines around here, listen, right over in here, some of them were pretty near professional clubs.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, these mines would give men jobs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hire.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of them didn't do nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: to beat rival town because where you had something like that your men was interested in, you could get good men around that place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cincinnati used to come to you a lot of times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's all there was around in this area.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there any professional league in this area when you were growing up?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I made a mistake, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I quit, I took a Huntington ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, there's a professional one here now, but it's a school-like.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I took a Huntington club.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a mountain state club.
[SPEAKER_00]: You managed it?
[SPEAKER_00]: supposed to pitch, but the war was coming on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had a bunch of kids.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was their father, their mother, their nursemaid, their secretary, and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: I collected, it was all percentage based.
[SPEAKER_00]: I collected twelve and spent twenty-four hundred.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never wanted a manager.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have to make up the difference yourself?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was taking on percentage business.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I was listed as a
[SPEAKER_00]: I pictured my payroll was about $1,400, I believe, for a chef's stay within that, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was on there about $250 or something, in a percentage of a gig.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I got rid of that thing, there'd be no percentage there.
[SPEAKER_01]: There's Welch in that league, and Bluefield, and Williamson, and those guys.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see, there was Ashland, Huntington, Welch, Bluefield, Logan.
[SPEAKER_01]: You remember these places?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was one more of them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Williamson?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Williamson was in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the cardinal out of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: That great outfielder that Cardinals had for a user.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: This is 41.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, about that, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you travel around between towns in that lake?
[SPEAKER_01]: Here?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Mountain State Lake.
[SPEAKER_00]: By car.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't very far.
[SPEAKER_01]: By automobile?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And were the ballparks very good parks?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they were for that place, the ballparks.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, Beckley had a team over there, and of course they were cheating in it, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Frank McCormick, you know, he was over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what the town spent a lot of money kept around you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Couldn't quit it.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you happen to get that hunting container?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you happen to get that hunting container?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Ray Ryan, he was active in promotion and things.
[SPEAKER_00]: I knew him when I was a boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a big man.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of his sons is president of some small little town, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ryan?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Ray Ryan.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he talked me into it, because he knew Toby left that thing alone.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you live in Huntington that year?
[SPEAKER_00]: I stayed there in Westbrook Stadium in Beckley.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, she'd come there.
[SPEAKER_00]: When were you married?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 25.
[SPEAKER_01]: After you were with the cops, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did your father take great interest in your baseball career?
[SPEAKER_00]: The old man was a ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where I got the curve from.
[SPEAKER_00]: Back years ago?
[SPEAKER_00]: Professionally?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he work with you as a boy?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yeah, he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd throw rocks, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what we did on the farm.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's all there was to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: Throw rocks and do stuff like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: After you got through holding corn?
[SPEAKER_00]: Digging corn?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was too young for that.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I wasn't in that part of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was around machinery in the Missouri Corps.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: And around machinery with Mary Hall and smokers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not down in the mines?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, that's in the mine, but them mines over there, they had big timbers of whitewash, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: It ain't like some of those mines are, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're not all alike.
[SPEAKER_00]: This man over there, I've got a picture of him now, he was a general superintendent where there was about ten governors in the wives.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wasn't that great?
[SPEAKER_00]: A white old man, he probably owned that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a political power in Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_00]: The governors meet at the White Supper Springs, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd bring them in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a nice home there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He took them down in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: in the mountains.
[SPEAKER_00]: My father worked down there for a lot of keys and the cooking was to, to, it was, says 50 years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: His women would go anywhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd put lamps on them and everything like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that cage, it drops, you know, maybe 50 miles an hour going in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: His women hollered and they grabbed the old man.
[SPEAKER_00]: The old man was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He grabbed him to hold him up with a clippings here.
[SPEAKER_00]: So when they come back out, when the governor said to old man, said, young man, said, that might have been one of my wives you was hugging on that day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, yeah, and we liked the clippings here.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was quite a mind zone for him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your dad then was, I bet, real happy, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he see a pitch for the Cubs?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, him and my mothers were a series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that in 1929?
[SPEAKER_00]: They got to see me pitch a little in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm glad they wasn't in Philadelphia at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I lost that one pitch to two men.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you in that game when they scored the 10 runs?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I would leave my best friend to Charlie Rood.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was the third one in.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was five of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Paulish went through and hit two off of me, went right through the hole.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, I'm trying to figure out yet what happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they pulled me, and there's two more that followed me.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I put the winning run on, and we lost it on this picture route.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course, now Hartnett, I had him and Beckett too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never caught all year that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when he hurt his arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: He made the difference, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who did the catching?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was Gonzalez and, oh, shucks.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know him well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Played with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: A lot of those things I forget.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Taylor.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a catcher in Gonzales.
[SPEAKER_00]: You say you had heartened at Beckley.
[SPEAKER_00]: When was this?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I brought it down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I brought several of those fellows in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: When were you at Beckley?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I lived around there, you see, all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd come back here and hunt fish, go to work and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never loafed much.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a... Did you own the club you mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have the ball club there?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I'd go back after I'd come home the seasons over and professional ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know why you mentioned Hart before.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I brought him down here to play an exhibition game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Charlie Root, he was a troubleshooter on the Milwaukee club.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd come to Charleston and play, and they'd come to Beckley and stay all night with the rest out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was on the Cobb team when they went up there?
[SPEAKER_00]: What was their regular team?
[SPEAKER_01]: Twenty-four, was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Twenty-four.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, let's see.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was, other than McGraw, it was the first baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Uh, let's look, I don't know about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Kellefer was a manager though, I don't know about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then later on they got McCarthy, what a great man he was.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was going to say, what did you think of Joe McCarthy?
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought the world of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did he...
[SPEAKER_00]: He just... Everybody liked him on the ball club.
[SPEAKER_00]: And his wife was, they called her babe in the garage.
[SPEAKER_00]: Woman of best nature, person always.
[SPEAKER_01]: He handled his players through just, they respected him so much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, they sure did.
[SPEAKER_01]: He could get anything he wanted out of them, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, he did.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did he say that day when he scored the 10 runs when he went back to bench?
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't say, he didn't say nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's nothing he didn't say.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hack Wilson did lose to his son out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He should have had his glasses on.
[SPEAKER_01]: What kind of a chap was Hack?
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought he was great.
[SPEAKER_00]: Him and me were pretty good friends.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, they give, uh, had his birthright for where he was born, at Martinsburg, West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was born at Martinsville.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Right on the line there, Maryland and, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they put him in the Hall of Fame here, and I had one of those 2,300 pages.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's the new one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is it?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's the same thing, only it's updated.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a kid from New York, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Looks just like him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's just out this year.
[SPEAKER_01]: Doesn't weigh quite as much.
[SPEAKER_01]: He can carry a little better.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Pat claimed West Virginia, though, but he was born in Martinsville, Virginia, or...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what they've got him in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Elwood City, Pennsylvania.
[SPEAKER_00]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was born in Martinsville.
[SPEAKER_00]: West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, they had another good one up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, there was a lot of Texans and Californians at this time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you know, there ain't nothing like what was in California and Texas.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, we got everything, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, being that West Virginia, I got coal when he's got apples.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, Forbes Carthy come in the other day, every man had to do a little bit of messin'.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Go as quick as he come in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He come late, he stayed away, and he'd be playin' cards and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, these Texans and Californians got the best of me in hackin', you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: They got everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, he got a fella by the name of Earl Webb.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd born across the line, right over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, when he come there, well,
[SPEAKER_00]: That took up the slack a little bit more than we get in Texas.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nah, Heck was a good hustler, great ball player.
[SPEAKER_00]: This live ball, he'd hit a hundred home runs, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was a good hustler.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just didn't take care of himself, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yeah, he got that way.
[SPEAKER_01]: His career was so short.
[SPEAKER_01]: We talked about putting him in the Hall of Fame, but he just wasn't around long enough, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He only was since 12 years here, but one of those wasn't much.
[SPEAKER_01]: He didn't have a full, only a couple of full years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they put him in this one in Washington.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, there's a lot of people who like to see him in Cooperstown.
[SPEAKER_00]: They figured he was a good man on a ball team, but he'd fight them, too, when he got upset.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a rough little guy, too, but the best natured.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could do anything to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd never get mad.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd always laugh when somebody else...
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the one in Cincinnati, you know, got popped off so much around there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was running a motel business up in there before I told you you saw it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ray... McClare?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a relief pitcher on Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forget.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, one day we was playing him in Cincinnati, and he threw at Hack.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he always rode Hack.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hack didn't like him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't care if people were writing him, but there were some guys he didn't want to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know the fella, I know him too.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we was playing one time there, and him and Hack got into it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was sitting on the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was one of them bench jockeys.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Hack walked, and he walked off the bag and went to the bench to get with Cough, Ray Cough, Ray Cough.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they tagged him out, of course, and big ol' Rixey got him out of there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, a paper wrote up where a fight is going to be in Cincinnati the next time that we play them.
[SPEAKER_00]: So there's a bunch coming back there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know it was coming.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't get no tickets.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was up on top of the stands and everywhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: They even said Capone was coming to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the time I was there when Capone had buses.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we played him a double header, and it was a lousiest ball game with no life in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nothing happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody thought a fight was going to be over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ray Kopp, he was, they didn't, nobody liked him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was one of the best yockeys.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did Capone come to many of the ball games in Chicago?
[SPEAKER_00]: He would, he'd come.
[SPEAKER_00]: Moran's and the Dugan boys, there were some games he'd had down there.
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a box, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: They had a box.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Capone was the big boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: They was rival gangs.
[SPEAKER_01]: More excitement than the Stanzan on the Field magazine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yeah, but they'd got a queue to the stuff they didn't do.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't do no cheap stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: They was after them politicians.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like Bill Thompson and all of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: The whole state of Illinois.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wasn't bad, but they was among, you know, among the seven white boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where did you live in Chicago?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I lived in two or three different places.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did your wife live with you there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you had a room with some, or had an apartment with some of the other... What they did now,
[SPEAKER_00]: That's old man Reagan's idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had several secretaries in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Beek was the president.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, not at this point.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was young, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: A five-year-old.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when you'd go in there, they'd call the office.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a bunch of apartments for married men to go to.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they'd take them around so they could kick it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Once at the North Park Hotel, I was at the Park Hotel, then once on Michigan Way, 3rd West.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know if they were out on Wilson Avenue or not.
[SPEAKER_01]: On the road, did you have the same roommate or did you change roommates?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, most of the time they had the same room.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was your room at once?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, our room was, I don't know, a couple of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bob Oliver would have to harden it a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or I don't know, just nobody picked a room like this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whoever the secretary or McCarthy was.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't hardly do that because you might become crashed.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a great organization.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the Wrigley organization was always, you know, he started with the horse and buggy and chicken, two in common.
[SPEAKER_00]: He built that up into one of the biggest
[SPEAKER_00]: fortune, and you got a raise every year you were there.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you wasn't good enough for a raise, you wasn't good enough to stay.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a special doctor.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got this picture of him, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the spring, the old man had everything cleared out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, when the women come in, they got some young children, you know, they'd catch a cold or something, just call us old Dr. Davis, and if he wasn't there, there'd be two more right in their home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, his idea was, it was clear, if one of them ballplayers had something wrong with their wife or their children, there's gonna be something wrong with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought, well, that's simple.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he just had to.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got pictures here, and he'd come in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the only one that was allowed in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: The doctors, and that's all.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nobody comes in the clubhouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now I think we're going to have crack games.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a trainer?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, Lockshell.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he trained the Bears, Chicago Bears.
[SPEAKER_00]: First trainer that they had, too, Andy Lockshell.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everything was perfect.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody rode on the trains, lower berths, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd ride no lower berth, no upper berth.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got into scheduling him where we had special training over in Pennsylvania, the World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: The old man always didn't want his horse.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he's the first one that started the ladies' day, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was right at that, too, now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Years ago, those ballparks were dirty.
[SPEAKER_00]: Women, they wore white dresses most of the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, her husband, he wants to go to the ballgame.
[SPEAKER_00]: She wants to go somewhere else.
[SPEAKER_00]: Old man Wrigley had this stand so he could eat on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Naturally, she becomes a fan and the woman is the best fan that there is right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first time we had it on Monday, it was $20,000 at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: For 10 cents, you know, that was a good one.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was hollering and stuff going on.
[SPEAKER_00]: You never really had to cut it down to $10,000 in the park.
[SPEAKER_00]: The woman is, she's, you give them one that's,
[SPEAKER_00]: baseball fan now.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was more radical than anybody else.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he just started a little later this day.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can show you pictures in there, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, he had more boxes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Expensive seating Yankee Stadium had.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sixteen thousand was in that box.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got some pictures in there where they're all around the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't get them to stand.
[SPEAKER_01]: I wanted very much to look at your pictures, but I wanted to get the interview, some more interview, too, because the pictures are brilliant.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was Mrs. Blake a great baseball fan?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did she go out to the game most of the times?
[SPEAKER_01]: She was there all the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did she get nervous in your pitching?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, that's where a ballplayer's wife
[SPEAKER_00]: It takes a terrible beating.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's going bad out there, especially a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're ahead one minute, and you're in trouble the next.
[SPEAKER_00]: The same way that man makes a boot out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, his wife is sitting there, and you've got to keep your mouth shut.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went in home, I worked, worked hard, and lost eight pounds, or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: She looked worse than I did, sitting up in the stand.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, now tell me about some of your great experiences with the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I got beat a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you won a lot, too, like in 1928, your best year.
[SPEAKER_01]: 17-11.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was starting regularly, that's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was...
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd start and then I could relieve.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was one of these fellas that never had much of a...
[SPEAKER_00]: So, McCarthy asked me lots of times, he said, can you help me a little bit today if I need you for a year or two, maybe I'll work.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, yeah, you always tell, I believe in when I ask you something, tell a yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Even if you didn't feel so good?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, because then,
[SPEAKER_00]: You're trying and you're taking that monkey off his back.
[SPEAKER_00]: They ask you if you feel all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: You say, I don't feel so good or something, and they put you in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: You might be a fella.
[SPEAKER_00]: Say, I don't think he ever done, but he might have been one, and I told him I didn't feel good.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't think he's anybody to do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got along with Joe good.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I thought he would go kiss me out on the mound one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never did.
[SPEAKER_00]: The White Sox, we played the White Sox, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd have more feet than the World Series could, but we put them on the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, you can't put them in the World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: You got the field stands and all that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was a hot to the north side of Union.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I said, I don't, I believe in being lucky all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Joe, we drove to Tennessee and he didn't hear nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was playing, coming out of the last ball game, and I was out managing a car, and I packed and hit my West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's more or less the last ten.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he sent Lockshaw out.
[SPEAKER_00]: We was out in the Pepperdine having a good time, sweating, and everything was going hot.
[SPEAKER_00]: He sent Lockshaw out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, Joe wants to see something.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went in and he says, I'm in trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: Can you help me today?
[SPEAKER_00]: Can you start?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll send somebody after you.
[SPEAKER_00]: He gets in trouble.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, yeah, I'm ready.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know where I was.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd worked a whole lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: And by joy, we was playing in their park.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got me five runs first inning, and all I had to do was be called.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, after the game was over, we beat them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe came out to me and I thought he was going to kiss me.
[SPEAKER_00]: You missed the whole game?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a great, great outfit.
[SPEAKER_00]: This fall, I'd say now, the whole time we was on the island, we never did see that far.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was interested in Arabian stagings.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're talking about Phil?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Puccini cars, imported cars.
[SPEAKER_00]: That old man was around the whole time, just like anybody.
[SPEAKER_01]: What were things like on the island?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, that was a great place.
[SPEAKER_01]: Must have been some spring you'd have out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see, Tom Nix had a home out there, Zane Gray, and I don't know, a lot of these people had homes over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd go across the channel.
[SPEAKER_00]: He owned his own boats, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Go across the channel, it was about 40 miles across there.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Pacific Fleet used to come through there.
[SPEAKER_00]: What they'd do, there was 26 battleships.
[SPEAKER_00]: There'd be 13 in the Pacific, 13 in the Atlantic.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they'd come through there, through San Diego Channel when we was there, and they had a team, I remember one of them was the Tennessee that had the championship.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd stop and play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joey Brown had a team that would come over there, and people, well, they'd buy a ticket on the boat and get lunch at the St. Catharines and the Glass Bottom Boats.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they came up to the ballpark all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a lot of crazy stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joey Brown had a good team.
[SPEAKER_00]: We tried to let them get them guys to beat us, but you can't show that or nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: McCarthy put some experienced men there, go lay the ball in there, but you couldn't let people know that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He never told them.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he lived right out of Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: His wife and kids were there, so the next day they had a special funeral for him, Cincinnati and all of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was at Pittsburgh when I went there.
[SPEAKER_00]: What would be the date on this?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is there a date on this?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: That'd be about 1930?
[SPEAKER_01]: It'll be close to that.
[SPEAKER_01]: That'd be nice to be a copy of.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is two great Irishmen.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's McCarthy and old Jimmy Burke.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe's companion and coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here's something now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, you get a lot from kids wanting autographs.
[SPEAKER_00]: They send, I got four dozen here one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But this one now, somebody's commercialized.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I won't never, I never do autograph them and send them back.
[SPEAKER_00]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_00]: That one's on, no, I believe that's in Cubs Park.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one in the coach park.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, that's a good one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one on the island where we trained.
[SPEAKER_00]: And here's where I come home and work is putting in high-tension lines through the mountain then.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't take your winters off, did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'd hunt for a while, but I wasn't going to loaf no more much.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where I got all that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had one span there, 1,600 feet.
[SPEAKER_02]: That must have been a job, putting those wires in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we had the equipment to.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had an engineer to put the swag in them, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: with temperature.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now there's the one in the Hall of Famers at Charleston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sam Huff was down there at that too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know hardly any of those fellas on there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought I might be the second oldest one, but I was the third one.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was one fella 78 and one 76.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll be 75 in September.
[SPEAKER_00]: that's taken at the city conservatory well let me see now we made it hit a thousand is that right i hit a ball and i hit a ball that a bird dog couldn't caught it on the ground twisted did everything i beat it over the back
[SPEAKER_00]: I was ashamed on it, but on paper a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: About a thousand, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: My mother saw that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_01]: Thank you very much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's Charlie and his son.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you know what these scorecards are worth today?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a lot of stuff here that none of us could buy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I bet you do.
[SPEAKER_01]: These are worth $25, $30 or so.
[SPEAKER_00]: Earl would do it, and then the manager had to build the wheel for drops.
[SPEAKER_01]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Dave Herman, Kit Houston, and Daddy Vance.
[SPEAKER_00]: There ain't nobody that can move it.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's nobody that can set up that thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's capable.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were farmers.
[SPEAKER_01]: Raised grapes.
[SPEAKER_01]: You met her when you were out on the coast?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I met her in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've been there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had to borrow money, too, to bring her back to West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_00]: I married and brought her back here, and I had to bring her back and borrow money.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wouldn't you nuts.
[SPEAKER_02]: And here's young Woody English.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got hit five times in the back.
[SPEAKER_01]: I see Woody English is the only one that didn't sign this picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: There's two of them over here.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sure?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, Woody didn't sign him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, here's a left-hand pitcher he signed.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, they have all the names though, don't they?
[SPEAKER_01]: I see the names in the bottom there.
[SPEAKER_01]: I'd like to have a copy made of one of these because that's a beautiful picture.
[SPEAKER_01]: But this other one's big.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's in here somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Isn't that one over on the floor, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: You can tell where the bowl's being hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's so right.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're making the break the same way.
[SPEAKER_02]: That person was English, was he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Woody wasn't, he was a little bit of a follower.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they, when he got married, they had an apartment right next to us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they?
[SPEAKER_00]: In an apartment hotel, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got the picture of him and her here, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Somewhere, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know who I talked to last Thursday?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Woody English's mother.
[SPEAKER_01]: You did?
[SPEAKER_01]: Is Woody, where's Woody at?
[SPEAKER_01]: Newark, Ohio.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: His mother's still living.
[SPEAKER_01]: Delightful little lady, 86 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Woody was a little guy, but he was dynamite.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's got bad arthritis now.
[SPEAKER_00]: He has.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was awful slim.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he looked just like a kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and he got married, and they come and got an apartment in the hotel we was in in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the picture's here.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's not married now.
[SPEAKER_01]: He isn't.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's just living with his mother.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe her name was Helen or something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: A little dark.
[SPEAKER_01]: I asked about her, but she didn't say much.
[SPEAKER_01]: Woody wasn't home.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, now, Woody's got to be 62 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Maybe a little older than that, but it's in his later 60s probably.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hornsby helped him out a lot now.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, Woody's on shortstop.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did Hornsby help him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he just helped him, told him what to do, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hornsby liked him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hornsby didn't mix with many people.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you and Hornsby get on?
[SPEAKER_00]: We got along alright.
[SPEAKER_01]: You got along pretty well with most of them, I imagine.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they all got along, I reckon.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hornsby was distant.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he, uh...
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't managing for you, was he?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was managing the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, when they got rid of McCarthy, they blamed McCarthy for losing that series, but it was not his fault, it was his players' fault for not having Hartnett in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they bought Hornby from
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe he gave a couple hundred thousand and four or five ballplayers going to Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: George Fuchs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't come over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you all smoke?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, go ahead and smoke.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's some Chesterfield here.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I've got some right here.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm so busy reading, I don't have time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, I may have some over here directly.
[SPEAKER_01]: Go ahead and tell me about Hornsby.
[SPEAKER_01]: as the manager there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Hornsby couldn't, I don't know, he was a loner in a way, but he took the Cardinals, you know, they fired Rickey.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, Rickey wasn't no big man with the Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm saying Braden was.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Braden had them crazy.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, Rickey did, technically.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had one heinie mewer that he wanted to give a sign of.
[SPEAKER_00]: In heinie, he'd start a fort and the bleachers would call the ball pit.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got rid of Hornsby and made a trade of the Cub for Bob O'Farrell.
[SPEAKER_00]: and Alexander, and he won the pennant and beat the Yankees, Hornby did, and he was way down.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had them young ballplayers there, too, Hornby was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ricky was the manager then, he had them all crazy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had the one fellow there, you know, I didn't know him.
[SPEAKER_00]: You heard about him building a boat in the basement, haven't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Never heard of him before?
[SPEAKER_00]: The old joke about somebody building a boat in the basement and can't get it out the basement door.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, how'd he build a pigeon coop?
[SPEAKER_00]: No horny, but he was, he was mechanical and I'd pitch to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: The ball, you could just see that much till you opened the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a ball, that close, and he had two stripes on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It looked like he wasn't ready to, but he'd got a piece of plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: You heard about what,
[SPEAKER_00]: Clem told the young pitcher, didn't she?
[SPEAKER_00]: Some young pitcher, old Bill Clem, all pitchers wanted him, but he was the master of all.
[SPEAKER_00]: So this boy kicked on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he says, young man, if that had been a strike, Mr. Hornaby would have let you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was scared of spikes all the time anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: In Chicago, the wind was bad there, and the English and the Grimm used to have to take him from flies all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He just looked like a mechanical man all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They would look at him like that and he really laid one down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never fooled, never looked at him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now did they let McCarthy go?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 1930?
[SPEAKER_01]: They didn't let him go right after the series.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe it was, it might have been 31.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe it was 31.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went over there one Saturday night.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a great fellow, McCoy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you with the Cousin 32 during the World Series?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I was 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I was at Columbus.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you, did Chicago release you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: They, Philadelphia, claimed me on waivers and went over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They finished the season, and that's when the Cardinals got me in the organization.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the feeling is that was during the Depression.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody was broke.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I finished the season with them, and then I went into the Cardinal organization in 22.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I went to... 32?
[SPEAKER_00]: 32.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when Dean and Bill...
[SPEAKER_00]: Lee?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, Slaughter came later.
[SPEAKER_01]: Jimmy Collins, was he with them?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: We played an exhibition game when I was at St. Louis.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Cardinals.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was for a hospital benefit, and that's where I come up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we played the Columbus Club there, and then they come down to Charleston, and they packed it, and that slaughter let off and hit me on the shin.
[SPEAKER_00]: It went back at me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I cut my hair and buried it down, and that was the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: Diaz was there, but his arm was hurt.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was up in the announcer's bush, you know, with Mike and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: He played the first baseman in the pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he gave my mother, she was there, an autographed ball I'd seen in the family somewhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now slaughtering them, I wasn't in the major leagues in that company.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course I did go back in on the day he broke his toe when I joined in Boston when he was 37.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a good husband and a young ball club there then too.
[SPEAKER_00]: If they got down, you see, Warnakee and Fallen did.
[SPEAKER_00]: A young club like that, you gotta keep up their spirits all the time, because something happened while they were trying to get down a little bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pepper Martin was there, and oh, I don't know, the husbands and young fellas, there was something.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd want a pig out to pitch it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, you were down to Columbus in 32.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And 33?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was, let's see, I was at Columbus Inn for a while and then went to Rochester, I believe, a bunch of us did.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you were with Rochester from then on for a while?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, let's see.
[SPEAKER_01]: What'd you do the rest of the next couple years?
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see, 34.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was in a cardinal organization then, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was with them with some club.
[SPEAKER_00]: We trained the Trice Institute group in Houston.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had four or five clubs down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rick would come over and make his speeches to all his managers, and you knew more than he did on the ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought Ricky was a great baseball man.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an organizer.
[SPEAKER_00]: He, on the ball field, he was, well, I've heard them say he was the dumbest man in the world.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was an organizer.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what I tell you, that he had to, when he was manager, he had to, oh, it was crazy, but, told Hines to go give him a sign what the pitch was.
[SPEAKER_00]: The people in the bleachers there in St. Louis called the pitch all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They knew just as quick as Hines did what pitch was coming.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd lecture, you know, he was a great lecturer.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a brilliant education, that man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Law degree and everything like he had.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he'd come up when the Depression come, and he got Brayden that had the money to go and see all the minor leagues went broke, where they trained these fellas.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had experienced men running all that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he went and bought them up, like to bring them to buy up all these during the Depression, all the ball clubs there.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you were with Columbus and Rochester then, would you deal with Ricky in signing your, negotiating your contract?
[SPEAKER_00]: I never, I've been, I never would.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wrote me one letter, I didn't even answer, and I've never played for him, but I'd heard so much about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had, when he was signing in for us to contract, men like Boblin getting $9,000 a year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some clubs had men sitting on the bench getting less than that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Happy never got to be catered.
[SPEAKER_00]: She catered him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hornsby was the real first man that ever got any money out of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gotta give a great sign to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, Fresh got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pretty good salary, of course.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fresh was...
[SPEAKER_00]: Traded to the Cardinals, or Hornsby.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hornsby was with the Giants at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Him and Grody.
[SPEAKER_00]: But no, Ricky wasn't making a speech.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a brilliant man, but he didn't belong on that board.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was too technical.
[SPEAKER_00]: Didn't know how to handle it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Get him to do what he wanted to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who were some of the toughest batters to pitch against?
[SPEAKER_01]: Them two wieners were the worst.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: They gave me more trouble.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why was this?
[SPEAKER_01]: They could get their bat at any pitch?
[SPEAKER_00]: They were so fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't have... you couldn't pick out a weakness on them.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd throw one in here, let up on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd think it'd be round on me, so I would slice it to the...
[SPEAKER_00]: by the field in the little way and lay it off.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then they had a right-hand hitter in between them, and they pulled the infield in on Paul, or on Lloyd, the little one.
[SPEAKER_00]: They took two steps in, because if that ball took two hops, they just would've pulled on to it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, and he played that big center field in Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: He outrun that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Paul, you couldn't get a man for upsetting
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe here'd come Paul up, he'd either hit or hit, and Paul would slice one down the line.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was in the plate all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't get him mad or nothing, not say nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to talk to one fella about, sometimes you run into somebody, might a ball player, and talk about the way
[SPEAKER_00]: I asked this guy, how did you get him out or something?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, ain't nobody getting out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, really?
[SPEAKER_00]: What's the best thing to do?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, shoot them.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the nicest fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were throwing out a little ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: You mentioned Bill Clem as a good umpire.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you find the umpires generally pretty good, capable people, and honest?
[SPEAKER_00]: Absolutely.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were the best.
[SPEAKER_00]: Their swords were ticked and screened.
[SPEAKER_00]: Most all of them were Irishmen.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went there too.
[SPEAKER_00]: You couldn't win the war.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you hear criticism of them sometimes that they're not alert, they're on top of the game and so on.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've seen ballplayers kick, now let them get out there and try and do their job, see what they're going to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that Clem, he was a psychologist to a 3-2 pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now that's a critical pitch.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's a hitter and a pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've got to be careful.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see him get out.
[SPEAKER_00]: square off like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you know the man's on top of the ball, what can you do?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm saying he always told the young pitchers to work fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: All good pitchers do work fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when the first game I pitched at his umpire, he brought the ball out to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, now young fella, let's have a good fast game.
[SPEAKER_00]: These people want to get home some year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, all good pitchers pitch fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I knew Alexander.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, look at Alexander.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he pitched fast all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Babe Herman, he didn't like Babe Herman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't like Drocher.
[SPEAKER_00]: So one time, we was playing and Arden started up at the plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't allow a grocery permanent to get in or plant it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he, Babe was out in Santa Fe and they was out there arguing.
[SPEAKER_00]: We looked up there and here comes Babe.
[SPEAKER_00]: He can't stand no longer.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's come from Santa Fe.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got about second place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill spied him about the same time we did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody said, look out on the bench there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill had that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He kept watchin', but Bill Clem, he'd draw a line.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you got the crowd to argue with him, you better not step over that line, it'd cost you money to do that, son.
[SPEAKER_00]: The way the babe got within about six feet of him, he drew that line, stepped back, and boom, just like baby, he had stomped off.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't let him and Droescher either one argue.
[SPEAKER_00]: Stroser was a great shortstop too.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a lot of gap.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Herman to pitch to?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was another one of them guys you didn't know what to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: You might bounce one up and he looked bad and do it again and you hit it out of the park.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know him very well?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, I played against him several times.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe he was in the Coast League when I was there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he crazy?
[SPEAKER_01]: He was in one of them, the three men on the front, but he's the one that caused it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted to run into these other guys, and they kept running back, and people hollered at the two outfielders that were running the ball down out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had the, that in St. Quinta was a great outfielder at Brooklyn, maybe you heard of him, in St. Quinta.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was a concrete wall, if it ain't so.
[SPEAKER_00]: far out there, and Zach, fly ball hit out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a lot of them, you don't know where he's gonna catch or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: So if Zach would stay there, there'd be a man on first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd say, well, if he sees you're gonna catch it, he's gonna start running.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd stay in there and catch it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd like to go catch it, and then he'd wheel right quick and bounce, bounce off and he'd catch it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the man takes on his
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't based on Herman tried that one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Turned around and turned around and he ain't right there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we just hoped he'd stay.
[SPEAKER_00]: They told more stuff about him, but he was dangerous up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd get on bases.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Hartnett one time, he got on there four times with us, and Hartnett kicked him off twice.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they say he always counted his baton average when he got there.
[SPEAKER_00]: The next time we saw him, Uncle Wilbert must have told him, when you get on first base, stay there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he never did get over there no more.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was absent-minded, would that be the way of describing him?
[SPEAKER_01]: No!
[SPEAKER_00]: You're not very bright, you're a fellow like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're too fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't think the right way.
[SPEAKER_00]: They can think plenty all right, but I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they always accuse a guy when he gets picked off for figuring up his batting average or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: Gabby Hartman.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was a great pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: They traded O'Farrell.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now Alexander O'Farrell was a high salaried man in the league and the best catcher, but they had this young Hartman there.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, they knew he was going to make it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they traded O'Farrell in.
[SPEAKER_00]: What Gabby was good at, he's so good about a pitcher now.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you got a man on first base, they had good base runners.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd run bases off him.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were all fast men.
[SPEAKER_00]: You didn't have to take your mind off that hitter and watch this fella.
[SPEAKER_00]: Keep him close there, because if he got off there, well, Hartnett would get him off of there.
[SPEAKER_00]: You got one man to concentrate on instead of two of the men on there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd throw that ball and pass you.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sometimes you'd have to fall off the mound and look like as though you'd hit the dirt and come up in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was an easy three-strike game.
[SPEAKER_01]: Where'd he get his nickname from?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: The Great Talker?
[SPEAKER_00]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: The Great Talker?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, in a way he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was always yacking and laughing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never saw him mad one time, I don't think.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was well like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about Jolly Cholly?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he your teammate?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I was with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was Pittsburgh, the first one that could.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was always, he was a Dutchman, you know, he had his fun.
[SPEAKER_01]: He always seemed to be laughing and playing the guitar or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a slow man, but he was about the best fielder I ever saw.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd kick some ball with his naked hand, toe the bag, and be up in front of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: For all's sake, Sisler was a great first baseman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come over in the lake, too, when he got through.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he was kind of at the end of the line then, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boston, old Jim Burke, I pitched against him one day.
[SPEAKER_00]: A fellow with glasses on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sissler you pitched against?
[SPEAKER_00]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: You pitched against Sissler?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he'd come to Boston that late.
[SPEAKER_00]: They can't see if you crowd them.
[SPEAKER_00]: The ball out there, they can see better.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we pitched
[SPEAKER_00]: Inside the sister there, of course he wasn't a hitter anymore, an old Jim Burke that managed him, I believe he managed him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He told me one day, I got him out the bowl, he said, I know one piece though, you throw that ball in and cut that first baseman down.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he couldn't see, you know, he's the first one I saw had glasses on.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't wear them then because it's pretty dangerous, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was wearing the glasses now?
[SPEAKER_00]: In his later years?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, later years.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come to the National League.
[SPEAKER_01]: I never saw a picture of him in glasses.
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't think I ever saw a picture of him in glasses.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, he's the first one.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the next one I saw was Chick Haley.
[SPEAKER_00]: Danny McFadden, remember that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I didn't see him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And George DePorcer.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wore glasses.
[SPEAKER_00]: That sister, he was a great hitter, baserunner.
[SPEAKER_00]: He must have been a great team man.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you're in a ball club everyday, you can hit more than a man.
[SPEAKER_00]: All that's causing trouble, you gotta get rid of that man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cause he can upset the whole thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, let me see what else I can find in here now.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had for a good many years told him what I wanted.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wanted something that, in California, for the flowers, nobody pays no attention to them at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I wanted to send something from the forest.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, the law, of course, it had to be artificial.
[SPEAKER_00]: Chestnut dogwood.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said that he thought he could do it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he sent it out there to Beckley, and here's what she wrote back.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was at Charlie's funeral there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He must have done a good job.
[SPEAKER_00]: They can do wonderful things.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the fellow Mayles, she's talking about Duster Mayles, he just died two or three days ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was amazing.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in the Coast League, too, when I was there in the 23s in San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he a funny man or a... Well... Babe Herman type?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had the stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he wasn't at World Series.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, 1920.
[SPEAKER_00]: In Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah, Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he had stuff now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I'll tell you, he was...
[SPEAKER_00]: a little bit deformed in a way, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh?
[SPEAKER_00]: In what way?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was his shoulders and his head.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a mason.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was well pleased with that, so I guess he didn't do a good job.
[SPEAKER_00]: She called a forest boat to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was all stuff from the mountains.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were many of them masons?
[SPEAKER_02]: Were many of these ballplayers Masons?
[SPEAKER_00]: There was 15 or 16 on it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you one?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was and dropped out of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got the ring in there the time when Miss Blake gave me one.
[SPEAKER_00]: There were several shriners.
[SPEAKER_00]: And McCarthy, all his coaches, were very... You know, years ago, all the umpires and ballplayers were all Irishmen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever barnstorm much?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, we did there in Rochester.
[SPEAKER_00]: One time, you know what we did?
[SPEAKER_00]: Eastman Kodak had the girls team.
[SPEAKER_00]: You ever hear of it?
[SPEAKER_00]: In Rochester?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, I think so.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a professional.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had some big Polish girl there and something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had John Miles and everybody like that, and they shut us out about seven to nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Couldn't nobody hit that ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was trying to swing too hard at it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Eastman Kodak had that team for a good many years, I guess.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever play against any black ballplayers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I played again in Baltimore at the Seasons over one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played against the Black Orioles, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's another team.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some black pitch skidder may like to war me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pretty good, huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you fellas talk much about there not being any black players or think much about it?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, never.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never came up, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Never thought about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: In history, she had two girls and they lived right up over it.
[SPEAKER_00]: The old man was an explosive man.
[SPEAKER_00]: His name was John Holder.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he built the CNO Railroad to.
[SPEAKER_00]: He died in what they called Miner's Adjunct.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where he got in that tunnel.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was about five years old when he died.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a rebel soldier.
[SPEAKER_00]: Grandma, she died living with my father and mother.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was about 90 pounds, and me and her used to get in to it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd try to kid her a lot, she could remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was in Richmond when Grant took it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were poor people.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she'd tell all that, and I'd have something to kid her.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd just pick her up sometimes, smack her on the rear.
[SPEAKER_01]: I said, get away from me there, boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, I said, Grandma, one time, I said, you know the reason them rebels got beat?
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, why?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, they couldn't shoot.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, they shot like them Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tell her all stuff, and she died thinking, she was 96, that she would get that pension.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's something that's in the Constitution, in the preamble or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: A rebellion in the country, you can't get it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They never did get any pension directly.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then all the rebellions that there is right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they never did rebel soldier.
[SPEAKER_00]: They never did get...
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe that's the women taking a ride.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just got off the boat or something and they're going up to the hotel.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to have something to tell her all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: My wife said, now Fred, you be careful.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, she could hold her own.
[SPEAKER_00]: a picture of the bridge gamers, Gabby's wife, he just got married.
[SPEAKER_00]: We got compartments right together going out to the coast.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now here's Woody and his wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's what followed now when I was on Columbus.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bip Wysong.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's from around there and he gave me a coon and he raised little raccoons and I got it and took it back with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Clubhouse boy took care of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wysong.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's from around there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's a picture of someone I was taking in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now this fellow was the head of the Buick, Northwest Buick.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had about 15 Buicks on them.
[SPEAKER_00]: His name was Carl Zamwock, I believe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who are those two on the left?
[SPEAKER_01]: You're on the right.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Charlie Root and Cliff Heathcote.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Clifton and Heathcote.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a fine little fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: He died a young too.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was Rick Stevenson like?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was quiet, one of the best followers of the chair we saw.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, he was an All-American in Alabama.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was tough on them bases.
[SPEAKER_00]: He won a game for me, of course, from a day's advance, driving and running.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the toughest man there was with two strikes on him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd talk like them southerners.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody'd say, Stevie, how do you do it?
[SPEAKER_00]: The guy'd give him two strikes, and he says, I've got his deck plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd guard that plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: He did it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rambo was with us one time.
[SPEAKER_01]: He has a lifetime batting average of .336.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stevie?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, and there are a lot of players in the Hall of Fame that are nowhere near that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Quiet, he never swore, and he never drank a bottle of beer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, he used to go across, play checkers with the firemen.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a big firehouse there, for example.
[SPEAKER_00]: One time in Chicago, Rabbit was on shortstop and Steve Smith, that field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rabbit was a little bit of a... Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: One of these pop flies went up, one of them kind, nobody knows who's got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: We both got there at the same time, and Stevie's a hard runner.
[SPEAKER_00]: He took them guys out off that double play, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he hit and rambled just like a bee shooting out of a pot.
[SPEAKER_00]: The rabbit went right up.
[SPEAKER_00]: We know he killed him.
[SPEAKER_00]: So anyway, he got straight in that rabbit.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was tough.
[SPEAKER_00]: He started looking around on the floor.
[SPEAKER_00]: We thought he's crazy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's looking for something.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's bridge work.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was off his bridge work, old as everybody out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a rambler, he found one piece and never did it again.
[SPEAKER_01]: He thought he was dead, he lost his bridge.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now that was Moranville, they say, the one he played for Stallings.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the guy that run Stallings crazy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Rabbit did.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was a shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was in where it was supposed to be, and he could pick men off them bases, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a picture of Mr. Blake down in Florida or somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Moranville's in the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he's about a 260 header, what do you think about that now?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, well now he's, he is 260, which is a lot better than 300.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was with that little buzzard too for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: She's an attractive woman.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's a Birmingham picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: I want to put that on the list.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you were with Birmingham in when?
[SPEAKER_01]: The 35 or 36 maybe?
[SPEAKER_01]: After you... 35.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fresco Thompson, did you know him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had that.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a very wealthy man.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh was he?
[SPEAKER_00]: What did he have his wealth from?
[SPEAKER_00]: His father run some kind of chain stores.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: He become a top executive.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess he still is, isn't he?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or isn't he now?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, he died.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: From their operation.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here we are in the Wrigley Building.
[SPEAKER_00]: From Chicago, getting ready to go to West Harris.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe Bush's brother there, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you call him Joe or Guy?
[SPEAKER_00]: We called him Old Black Joe, Gummy.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know what, he was dark, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pat Malone was the one that named a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah?
[SPEAKER_00]: Stanton Fetchett.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't like it either.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's Uncle Charlie Moran, you know, he's the one that coached Little Center College with Bull McMillan and run over everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: You remember that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said I didn't know he was connected with it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he coached Center College, Charlie Moran.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's the umpire?
[SPEAKER_01]: Later umpire?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the umpire, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He coached Southern Center.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which one is he now?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here, that's the umpire there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Les Bell.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Hartman.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the bad boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's Uncle Charlie right there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He took that little center college and walked through all of Bo McMillan, I think.
[SPEAKER_01]: Is this the Wrigley Field?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's at Wrigley?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: They got people sitting in the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a lot of them out there.
[SPEAKER_01]: There was a Joe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one of Joe Brown.
[SPEAKER_01]: Y'all saw that one, Warnicke.
[SPEAKER_00]: Last I heard of Warnicke, he was a juvenile judge at Hart Spring Park.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a sheriff for a while, wasn't he?
[SPEAKER_00]: He come from Mount Idy too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was that comedian on there?
[SPEAKER_01]: Weaver, Charlie Weaver.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I guess it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now there's some power right there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wilson, Stevenson, Hornsby, and Cotter, right?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's right.
[SPEAKER_00]: These are wonderful pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you get all these pictures?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, I never did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Sometimes I'd get one and give it to her.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know where she got them.
[SPEAKER_02]: She did a terrific job.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was a wonderful historian.
[SPEAKER_00]: These probably stuck.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's all fouled up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether they've seen it or not.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now here we are in that wagon, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: We just got off the boat going to St. Catharine.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had some great times, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, here's another one of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They took pictures of everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I reckon that's the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm not sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't look tough enough in that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't like it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, here you are now.
[SPEAKER_00]: You want to see some hats?
[SPEAKER_00]: She wouldn't let me show that to nobody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Isn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Aren't they something?
[SPEAKER_01]: When would that have been now?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, it's in the 20s or somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: Aren't they something?
[SPEAKER_02]: They're all coming back.
[SPEAKER_02]: Those hats are coming back.
[SPEAKER_01]: Those are all wives?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't know who all of them are on there.
[SPEAKER_00]: This would be your wife here, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's back here?
[SPEAKER_00]: She got on the little hat.
[SPEAKER_01]: The little hat?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: I thought that would be her there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah, that's her.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now this is Mrs. Root.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's Hank Wilson's wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's an outfielder, John something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is Schulte, John Schulte's wife.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were the Y's very close?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: Were the Y's pretty close as well?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, well, he better be on that doorframe.
[SPEAKER_01]: Seems like a pretty close-knit outfit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Wrigley had a lot to do with it, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he just wanted everybody satisfied.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have any troublemakers that he got rid of at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, you didn't get those kind of people.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever play hearts?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now that's a game of arguments.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they played that on that club to start an argument.
[SPEAKER_01]: Here's one in the solarium at Santa Catalina.
[SPEAKER_00]: Do you know the guy's got the queen of spades in his hand?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's getting ready to unload, Darryl.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's been over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that's Percy Jones.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the one in Columbus that fell out of the wind and broke both legs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Percy Jones?
[SPEAKER_00]: Percy Lee Jones.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is Hartnett.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is me.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is Earl Webb.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Gonzales, Joe Bush, Clyde Beck, John Butler, Osborne, he's from down at El Paso.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Yoder and Percy Jones.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yoder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Y-O-T-E-R. Elmer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Elmer Yoder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, he's getting ready to be an argument.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody start that dead bird game and get an argument on that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: I roomed with Osborne.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, he lived at El Paso, born and raised.
[SPEAKER_00]: We come through there a couple of times when the rebels had war heads.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went over there, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we saw more fun.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could go to the, as far as it was running, the big shots stayed at Paso North, the hotel across the border.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd walk across there and nobody would pay no attention.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we saw, this was with two Mexican officers and something like that, and we'd ask who that fellow was.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was the dirtiest, filthiest-looking once that I ever saw in my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had some .30-30 rifles.
[SPEAKER_00]: Somebody had sold them to him over here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Twenty-two bullets went right through him.
[SPEAKER_00]: So we saw some big guy, it was all funny the way it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had on a uniform, braid on, long tail coat.
[SPEAKER_00]: We asked who it was, they said, Biggie General, I'll show you something.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was one of these doorman's uniforms they had on.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you know it opened cab doors and things like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a big time there with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, and they, that wasn't, that's after Villa, they killed him, I forget now who it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: They started a revolution down there about every three years.
[SPEAKER_00]: They seized that money and the Federal troops was a thousand miles away from them in Mexico City at the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd get there while they done scattered out, they ain't got no uniforms.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went in the barracks, they was filthy.
[SPEAKER_00]: They give them a piece for a day, it's 50 cents.
[SPEAKER_00]: They took their families with them in trains, their goats and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: This fellow Osborne, you ought to hear him tell what happened there, but they started to shoot across the border there one time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They kept the soldiers on the border all the time in this country, did the Mexican border.
[SPEAKER_00]: So them soldiers, the real grand, you know, you can walk across, they just drive most of the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They went over there after them, caught every one of them asleep up in a big canyon up there and said they had made bombs out of cow hides and everything that there was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: This fellow Halsman, he was dry anyway, but he'd get to tell this stuff about them Mexicans in the war over there, and boy, he kept everybody laughing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Mr. Blake, I put this picture of Mrs. Blake mending your sock.
[SPEAKER_02]: right in the top of this to straighten it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay?
[SPEAKER_02]: Because it's all wrinkled there.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a picture of jumping rope there.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's on the album.
[SPEAKER_02]: I want you to know where I put it, though.
[SPEAKER_02]: I put it in that scrapbook so we straighten it out, hopefully.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I didn't touch those.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you travel like this most of the time, all dressed up in suits and ties?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's about dinner.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, that's after dinner there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you dress for dinner most of the time?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, just about like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody wore white shirts.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this because it was just customary or did Mr. Wrigley want you to?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, everybody wore white shirts.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you picture them dressing like that today?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you wore what you'd take on the road.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd usually have a dark suit and a gray.
[SPEAKER_00]: brown shoes, not them black shoes, and a black pair, and he wore collars, two-step collars, detachable collars.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when it started out.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's after dinner, I believe, there.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the solarium, they called it the sunroom.
[SPEAKER_00]: Good-looking group there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, there's going to be arguments start there like crazy.
[SPEAKER_00]: I caught a goat out on the island, Charlie and Miss Ruth, wife and myself, after the latter part of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: They let you get in shape yourself.
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't tell you what to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's your job.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know how to get in condition to run and all stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: So one day an old man rigged a head on there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had horses, cars.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had some old Cadillacs, old ones.
[SPEAKER_00]: on there, so we decided to see the other side of the island, Charlie's wife and my wife and myself and Charlie.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Miss Ruth was driving and one of these old Cadillacs at the top comes off, you know, or goes back, and there was an old goat across the road.
[SPEAKER_00]: She had two kids.
[SPEAKER_00]: I jumped out of the car.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw they were weak, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: She just
[SPEAKER_00]: My wife said, where you going now, you nut?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'm going to catch a wild goat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's nutty to say that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're wild.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I went down in the canyon.
[SPEAKER_00]: It kept running, getting away.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this old goat, where she run at, the females got them goats out there, got horns.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she crossed on Old Road and Charlie, and his wife and my wife went on to look at the other side of the aisle.
[SPEAKER_00]: When they come back, I had that little one.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was so weak, you know, it couldn't run.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was tired, and so the wife, she knew I was always doing something, said, you got it now, what are you going to do with it?
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, we'll bring it back out here tomorrow evening.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, when the sun goes, it won't be down and it'll be cool out there on the island.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the breeze company.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they took it in to
[SPEAKER_00]: the town, they got a baby's bottle and fed it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they took it up to the clubhouse, and this fella stay there at nighttime, they covered it up, you know, and fed it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Mrs. Vaughn, he wrote on the tribute, I don't know if you ever heard of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Irving Vaughn?
[SPEAKER_00]: Irving Vaughn.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I got a little picture of that in there of her.
[SPEAKER_00]: and a goat.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so anyway, the fellas would go take care of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: We was in there playing cards.
[SPEAKER_00]: There wasn't no time there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so she heard about the goat.
[SPEAKER_00]: My wife come in and said she wanted to go out and see it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, y'all go on out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They let you in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I had to go out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she saw it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she wanted me to give her the goat.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, no, I'm not going to give you that goat.
[SPEAKER_00]: It'll die.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's mother will be back there looking for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: She talked me into it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the next day she had a little string on to yell at me.
[SPEAKER_00]: She kept that thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went back out there this spring.
[SPEAKER_00]: Next spring it was
[SPEAKER_00]: running around in the town.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was one in the Portuguese.
[SPEAKER_00]: They figured took them in there before Columbus come in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they was millions of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: We killed a lot of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they started making some dams back in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had to drag them out, you know, out of the canyon.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I helped drag one out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't kill them all.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I got the picture in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Dorothy Root, she's the only one living now.
[SPEAKER_00]: that was there when I caught that goat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's something to tell somebody that you caught a while ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes it is.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was a dirty trick.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you can tell them later on how you caught it.
[SPEAKER_01]: You had some great times.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a great life, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you had good training.
[SPEAKER_00]: All that training's pretty hard because if you don't get
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one I had with her now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, there'd be some young ballplayers come on the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd have about 45 of them out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wasn't going to take hard of his job or hardness or none of that, but they wanted to take a look at him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, they borrowed money and got him dented and come out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: When we started to leave, when we went back home,
[SPEAKER_00]: The mainland, that's where they started scattering.
[SPEAKER_00]: You've probably never seen them.
[SPEAKER_00]: She'd ask me what I thought they was going to do with so-and-so, and I said, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, when he gets over there, they know what they're going to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, well, it don't seem fair to nice kids like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, now listen, that boy and that girl's going to take your job with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: before she could see, well, she didn't think it was fair anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell her they're training them, taking a look at them, and the future views.
[SPEAKER_00]: But a lot of them, you never see or hear of.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, at least you had a satisfaction of knowing you made it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was lucky, I know it, that they was some men, they was a lot of good ball players back then.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, but you had something, or you wouldn't have made it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You have to get them breaks, too, and them jump on it, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know there was better ball player pitchers in the minor leagues than I was, but they just didn't get the breaks.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of us fellas didn't have such a good record in the minor leagues, but they'd take a shot at them, and they stayed there ten years.
[SPEAKER_01]: What was your best pitch?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: What was your best pitch?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think the curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like to over... See, all pitchers was overhand.
[SPEAKER_00]: They threw overhand and overhand curveball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because a sidearm curveball pitcher, he can't throw that to a left-hander.
[SPEAKER_00]: The ball's coming into him and he can fall away, but this other one goes...
[SPEAKER_00]: I was considered pretty fast.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got one
[SPEAKER_00]: clipping in there, Spud Davis, did you know him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Spud, he was at Philadelphia.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was in the southern, he come in the southern leg, went down there and he told him something about me in the southern leg, he compared me and Diaz, well I didn't compare to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said I was as fast as Diaz, but he had better control, which Dean did, he threw that
[SPEAKER_00]: high fastball, which you usually don't do about the time it'd get up to a hitter and start going up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he had such remarkable control.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he had.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got nine or ten strikeouts one game, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you walk quite a few people?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what I was.
[SPEAKER_00]: I might have walked two and strikeout two.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I was considered a wild pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: You hit many people?
[SPEAKER_00]: Hit many?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I never hurt none of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was afraid of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said something one time that I shouldn't have said.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Giants and Cardinals were fighting for, and I had good luck with the Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the Cardinals were in first place, and the Giants were a couple of games out.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was pitching to him and the Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was going very good.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they sent a follower by the name of Jack something.
[SPEAKER_00]: I forget.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was wild.
[SPEAKER_00]: He does show good hair.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Scott.
[SPEAKER_00]: So McGraw told him to hit me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know he did, and he hit me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he wanted to win a ball game, but our position was set, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got mad, and I went down to...
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't put him in, you see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jack Scott's relieved until I come in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had been sure it didn't hurt, and I went down to Bill Terry's office.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, Bill, we ain't going nowhere.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, get ready and you serve my guns now.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're going to have some fun.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, sure, but leave it to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, the guy said, don't worry about it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, anyway, if I had hit somebody unintentionally and done that and told him, of course, Bill was a real fella.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd never said nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, well, look what's falling out of my mouth what I've done.
[SPEAKER_00]: So anyway, I was waiting on Scott.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wasn't going to hit him in the head, but I was going to drop him.
[SPEAKER_00]: McGraw pulled him out of there to protect him, you know, and he used him for a pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: We beat them, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: They never got a good foul off me after that, because I was better if he let me sleep out there or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: He might have had a chance.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's a picture of a storm on the island.
[SPEAKER_00]: That happened in February.
[SPEAKER_01]: That channel got me up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's a picture of West Virginia.
[SPEAKER_00]: Made of Charleston, not Tula.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you know Greasy Knee?
[SPEAKER_01]: I interviewed him once.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here he is, right here.
[SPEAKER_00]: A little sleepy Glenn.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I don't know who else.
[SPEAKER_00]: George Stewart.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had something down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what it was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever get into many arguments with umpires over pitches?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Never got thrown out of a game?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, sure I did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Let's see, I got thrown out of a game when I managed in this league.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't do all of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They was led for me anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cost me $10.
[SPEAKER_00]: So no, I just didn't go.
[SPEAKER_00]: They never lost me in ballgaming and they never won me in ballgaming.
[SPEAKER_01]: It must have been a great thrill in 1929, winning that pennant.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did that feel?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it wasn't we won the pennant, but when it finished.
[SPEAKER_00]: It took all the joy out of it, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one when I joined the base.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, I pissed with my fingers broke, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: What was that?
[SPEAKER_00]: I got them broken on the 28th, I believe.
[SPEAKER_00]: But this one here, there's one of them balls hit in front of you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I drive the worst of his.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't tell where it's going.
[SPEAKER_00]: I stuck my hand and broke this one.
[SPEAKER_01]: How could you pitch after that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I just started holding the ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Faking a whole lot of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I pitched more underhand then.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you didn't pitch at all for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, no, about a week or something like that, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did it have to, did it affect your... Well, the curveball it did, you couldn't, you know, grip it, it was kind of, so it broke it in here and there, and it fell in there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Could you get a picture of us together?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Be careful of my picture, I'm flattening.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's some of what, I don't know where that's at.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, it looks like they're having fun.
[SPEAKER_02]: yeah i think we're looking at a picture here together while she's can you maybe can you get the two of us yeah well here do you want there you want to change or no just look together at this picture so yeah okay very good that's a good picture there yeah because they're all in shorts so it must be later but did women wear shorts in 1927
[SPEAKER_00]: Here I am feeding old Jake.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a nice little zoo at Kissimmee where I trained and I'd go out there every morning and feed Jake there.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the zoo there, old Jake.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one of them crazy pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Gonzalez and me on a lake.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the trip where we're playing cards with Hartman's wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here we are getting off the boat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one made on the way over Santa Fe.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's Annie Lockshaw pulling it.
[SPEAKER_02]: All those photographers must have gone crazy out there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Old man Wrigley, we had a carload of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And sport riders.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's one now.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember her, a great actress, in this part here.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was taken out in the studio, but I don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: The silent films?
[SPEAKER_00]: Silent films.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Hoot Gibson, Douglas Fairbanks.
[SPEAKER_00]: We went out to see him make Fairbanks make Thief of Baghdad.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm going to tell you how old I am.
[SPEAKER_00]: here's a man you going to or from the coast oh boy oh your wife's like me i'm always saving stuff i just who is this fellow here that face looks familiar tonight that's a young college boy i forget what his name is you're warren brown well that's why that's where i'm at
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Warren Brown was one of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Chicago writer.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Ray Shaw, he'd come over to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the one who caught that crooked series.